http://www.realvnc.com/en/legal/#purchase-terms

RealVNC
Products
Featured products
VNC® Connect
Simple, secure, ready-to-use remote access software for professionals and enterprises
VNC® Developer
Toolkits and solutions for integrating secure, real-time remote access
VNC® Viewer Plus
Lights-out remote access for Intel Core vPro computers
Solutions for...
System administrators and IT experts
Provide a consolidated remote access and support strategy for your business
Busy professionals
Seamlessly connect to and support people and devices wherever you are
IoT and embedded engineers
Create management and monitoring solutions for low-footprint devices
Hobbyists and makers
Educate and innovate, free for non-commercial use
Friends and family
Help and support on up to 5 computers, free for non-commercial use
Company
About us
Executive team
Read about the history of VNC® technology, and meet the executive team
Communications
Blog
Business and technology insights to help evolve your remote access strategy
Press releases
All our latest product and company news
Media coverage
Publications we've featured in, and industry news related to remote access
Careers
Current opportunities
We're hiring! Join our world-class, multi-disciplinary team in Cambridge, UK
Contact us
Language (English)
Sign out
RealVNC® uses cookies. For more information, please read our privacy policy.
Got it
All our legal information
Please contact us if you require more details or clarification.
Summary
RealVNC® is a registered Private Limited Company.
Company Registration Number (CRN): 04446945VAT Number: 758 1947 85
RealVNC® is the only organization able to offer commercial licenses to embed remote control and access capability into third-party products and services.
Copyright and trademarks
RealVNC®, VNC® and RFB® are trademarks of RealVNC Limited and are
protected by trademark registrations and/or pending trademark
applications in the European Union, United States of America and other
jurisdictions. Other trademarks and logos are the property of their respective owners.
Patents
VNC® is protected by UK patents 2481870, 2491657; US patent 8760366; EU patent 2652951
Purchasing terms and refunds
Purchases on account must be settled within 30 days. RealVNC® reserves
the right to add late payment and interest charges to the balance of
any outstanding accounts.VAT, where applicable, is included in the price.
Customers have the right to withdraw from the
purchase within fourteen working days of the day after the date the item is
delivered. This applies to all products except for software which has
been downloaded. All other refunds will be given at the discretion of
the Company Management.
T&Cs
The use of RealVNC® services is governed by these Terms and Conditions.
End User License Agreements
The use of VNC® Connect application software is governed by an End User License Agreement, which you can read in English, Deutsche, Français, Español, or Português.
The use of VNC® Connect application software specifically on Raspberry Pi is governed by this End User License Agreement.
The use of the VNC® SDK is governed by this Evaluation License Agreement.
The use of VNC® Viewer Plus application software is governed by this End User License Agreement.
Third party software acknowledgements
Third party software incorporated in VNC® Connect is acknowledged here.
Third party software incorporated in the VNC® SDK is acknowledged here.
Third party software incorporated in VNC® Viewer Plus is acknowledged here.
Privacy policy
This section sets out when and how we use your personal information that you or others provide to us.
If you are in the European Union and your organisation requires RealVNC to sign a Data Processing Agreement in order to meet your regulatory
requirements (for example, GDPR) to enable you, as Data Controller, to enter into a contractual agreement to use our services, please email privacy@realvnc.com and we will send our standard DPA for you to review.
Who are we?
We are RealVNC Limited, an English company (RealVNC).
Our registered address is Betjeman House, 104 Hills Road, Cambridge CB2 1LQ.
How do we use your data?
When you purchase or try our software
When you purchase or try our software, we will use your personal information to complete your purchase. The details we collect from you will include your email address, name, address, payment and other contact details.
If you purchase our software, we share your personal information with our subcontractors who are involved in the purchase process, such as payment providers, as well as credit reference agencies who we use to assess fraud, credit and/or security risks.
We need to process your personal information in this way to enter into and perform the contract for your use of our software.
When you sign up for a RealVNC® account
When you have a RealVNC® account with us, e.g. because you have purchased or tried our software, have signed up to our developer sandbox, or are using certain account-dependent functionality in our software, we collect your name, email address, phone number, country and whether you are using our software for business or personal purposes.
We need to collect and handle your personal information in this way to perform the contract for the use of our software.
When you use our VNC® Viewer software
Your information is only collected or handled if you have signed in to VNC® Viewer with your RealVNC® account, or if you have allowed the collection of usage data.
When you use your RealVNC® account to sign in to VNC® Viewer, we collect and handle information about your sign-in so you can identify exactly where you’ve signed in from. The details we collect include application name and version, local user name, computer description, machine name, device name, device type, and OS name and version. This information is cleared if you sign out of VNC® Viewer.
When signed in to a VNC® Viewer with your RealVNC® account, we also collect information about computers in your VNC® Viewer Address Book. The details include any name you have assigned to a computer in your address book, the address to use when connecting to it (e.g. a hostname, IP address, port/display details, or other identifier), the public key to expect when connecting to that computer, the default user name to use for authentication, the time of last connection, any configured labels for the address book entry, and an optional screenshot taken during the last connection. You can clear this information at any time by deleting the relevant address book entries from VNC® Viewer.
When you use VNC® Viewer’s Instant Support capability, we collect chat transcripts logging information about activities in the session. Logging information includes the timings and results of activities such as session start/end, file transfer, elevation requests and reboot attempts. This information allows us to provide you with historic details of instant support sessions you have been involved in. All chat transcripts are encrypted at-rest on our servers.
We need to collect and handle your personal information in these ways to perform the contract for your use of our software.
When you use the Instant Support Application, or when you receive support from someone using VNC® Connect’s Instant Support capability, you download and run the Instant Support Application. During the support session, we collect chat transcripts logging information about activities in the session. Logging information includes your IP address and the timings and results of activities such as session start/end, file transfer, elevation requests and reboot attempts.
We need to collect and handle your personal information in these ways to perform our contract for the use of this software.
When you use our VNC® Server and VNC® Viewer applications, if the ‘send usage data’ option is enabled, we will use our own systems as well as selected third-party analytics providers to collect and process the following information:
Device/machine information, such as machine name, network name, brand, manufacturer, model, operating system version and IP address.
Version, mode and subscription information.
Information about paths through the software.
Frequency that features are used, and how they are used.
Summary information about remote control sessions established, including (but not limited to) encryption type, protocol version, preferences set, duration and locale.
For the avoidance of doubt, we explicitly do not log or collect passwords, mouse clicks or keystrokes. These are encrypted end-to-end and are never available either to RealVNC® or to third parties.
This data may be used for product improvement, to tune the system, support technical decision-making, inform choices for a better user experience, and to validate and improve our model of user behaviour.
The collection of this data can be prevented by disabling the ‘send usage data’ option in the VNC® Server and VNC® Viewer applications.
When you set up our VNC® Server software
Your information is collected to perform a licence check, to provide service, or if you have allowed the collection of anonymous usage data for analytics purposes.
If you have enabled cloud connectivity for VNC® Server, we will collect and process information to allow you to license the application correctly, identify the computer and remotely connect to it. The details collected include application name and version, machine/device name and form factor, OS name and version, and MAC addresses.
If you are licencing VNC® Server with a licence key directly, we will perform an online audit to evaluate whether provisioning complies with the EULA.
We need to collect and handle your personal information in these ways to perform the contract for your use of our software.
When you contact us for customer services purposes
When you phone, email or message us using our website portal or online chat service, we may also handle your personal information (your name, contact details and the other details you provide to us) in order to provide the customer services you have asked us to. This could be when you ask us to confirm whether a particular product is available, or explain how our delivery or returns process works. Please be aware that we may record calls for training and monitoring reasons.
We rely on your consent to handle your personal information in this way, except when we are providing a service you have asked us to as part of the contract between us. Please keep in mind that if you do not provide us with the personal information we request from you for customer services purposes, we may not be able to fully answer your queries.
If you have signed up for our newsletter, blog or UX list
If you have opted in to receive marketing communications from us, we will use your name and email address to provide you with marketing communications in line with any preferences you have told us about.
If you have signed up to our UX list, we may invite you to take part in UX testing, invite you to let us know your thoughts on our products and to complete our UX and product surveys. During this process we may also ask you to provide details about your employer, your role and where you work, to help us better interpret the results of your feedback.
When we send you marketing emails, we rely on your consent to contact you for marketing purposes. Every email we send to you for marketing purposes will also contain instructions on how to unsubscribe from receiving them.
You are not under any obligation to provide us with your personal data for marketing purposes.
You can tell us that you do not want your personal information to be processed in this way at any time by contacting us at privacy@realvnc.com or, where relevant, by following the unsubscribe link shown in every marketing communication you receive from us.
Where you have spoken to us at an event
When you speak to us at an event, we will collect the following information from you: name, address, email address and phone number.
We collect this information so that we can keep you up to date with our services and pursue business opportunities with you.
Where we have obtained your personal information from a third party
We sometimes obtain your personal information from a third party provider where you have consented to them passing on your details to us, and we believe our software or services are relevant to you.
We collect your information in this way because we have a legitimate interest to promote the success of the business.
To make our services better
We use your personal information and also share your aggregated, anonymous data with third party analytics and search engine providers for the purposes of improving and optimising our services.
We process your data for this reason because we have a legitimate interest to provide you with the best experience we can.
When you sign up for a Home subscription
We may analyse your usage data together with your account data to assess if the usage purpose matches the selected licence type (non-commercial only). Based on this assessment we may decide to contact you to discuss your use case and whether other subscriptions might fit you better.
We do this because we have a legitimate interest in enforcing the terms and conditions of our contracts.
If our business is sold
We will transfer your personal information to a third party:
If we sell or buy any business or assets, we will provide your personal information to the seller or buyer (but only to the extent we need to, and always in accordance with data protection legislation); or
If RealVNC® or the majority of its assets are acquired by somebody else, in which case the personal information held by RealVNC® will be transferred to the buyer.
We process your personal information for this purpose because we have a legitimate interest to ensure our business can be continued by the buyer. If you object to our use of your personal information in this way, the relevant seller or buyer of our business may not be able to provide services to you.
In some circumstances we may also need to share your personal information if we are under a duty to disclose or share it to comply with a legal obligation.
When you apply for a job with us
We will collect and handle the data you provide to us on your application and/or CV on the basis of your consent. This information may include sensitive or special categories of personal data, such as your race, ethnic origin or information about your health.
Where you have provided employment references to us as part of your application, we will contact those referees and ask them to provide a reference about you. As part of this process, we will disclose your name and the fact that you have applied to work with us to your referees. We also use the information you have provided to us when applying for jobs to record who is applying for jobs with us and to make sure we are attracting a diverse range of applicants.
You can withdraw your consent by contacting us at privacy@realvnc.com, but if you choose to withdraw your consent, we will be unable to process your job application any further.
Please also see our recruitment-specific privacy notice.
To decide when and how we get in touch with you
We may analyse your usage data together with your account data and our history with you to decide when and how to get in touch.
An example may be if a new version of the software is coming out and we think it’s relevant to you or if we would like to ask for your feedback on a specific feature.
We process your data for this reason because we have a legitimate interest to provide you with the best experience we can. You may opt out of receiving such communications by contacting privacy@realvnc.com.
What about technical information and analytics?
Information we collect about you
When you visit our site, we will automatically collect the following information:
Technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, screen resolution, operating system and platform; and
Information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators, clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time), page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs) and methods used to browse away from the page.
Information we receive from other sources
We are also working closely with third party advertising networks, analytics providers, hosting providers and search information providers from whom we may also receive general aggregated anonymous information about you.
We will combine the information you provide to us with information we collect about you.
What about cookies?
Our site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our site and also allows us to improve our site. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.
A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer. We only use (and store) non-essential cookies on your computer's browser or hard drive if you provide your consent.
Cookie
Purpose
More information
Session cookies
For the correct operation of our websites
This type of cookie is essential to the correct operation of our websites. For example, they allow you to remain logged in to your account while visiting different pages on our websites, or conduct an online chat with our sales or support teams.
User preference cookies
To remember your choices about what content to show you
For example, your choice of currency, the last state of different UI elements on the websites, etc.
Social media cookies
Third-party cookies used by social media platforms when sharing content
We make it easy to share content from our website on social media by including sharing buttons, provided by third party social media platforms. These third party buttons may include the use of cookies, which we do not have any control over.
VWO cookies
To generate heatmaps of the most popular areas of our websites
This information is used to tailor and improve our sales and marketing flows.
Hubspot cookies
To track repeated interactions with our websites and collateral over time
We want to make sure that we’re doing the best job we can at putting the right information in front of people. By understanding where and how people click and browse our site, we can spot where we’ve not done as well as we could, and improve our websites for the future.
Content delivery network cookies
To serve websites quickly and efficiently
We sometimes use 3rd party partners to serve our website so that you always see it quickly and responsively. Third party providers of such services may use cookies to help make this more efficient.
Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, which we do not have any control over. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.
You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.
Except for essential cookies, all cookies will expire after 2 years.
Where do we store your data?
We may store and transfer personal information either within or outside of the European Economic Area (EEA). We transfer data in such a way where it is necessary to fulfil:
Your requests and requirements in respect of our software and services; and
Certain business functions that we use a third party business partner to provide, which may include the provision of sales and marketing assistance, data analysis and data cleansing services.
Where we transfer your personal information outside of the EEA, we ensure it is protected by making sure at least one of the following safeguards is in place:
By transferring your personal information to a country that has been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection by the European Commission;
By using specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give your personal information the same protection it has within the EEA; or
Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between Europe and the US.
To keep this privacy policy as short and easy to understand as possible, we have not set out the specific circumstances when each of these protection measures are used. You can contact us at privacy@realvnc.com for the details as to how we protect specific transfer of your data.
How long do we retain your data for?
We will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any accounting or legal requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for the personal information we hold, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal information, the risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal information, the reasons why we handle your personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. If you require further information about our specific retention periods, please contact us at privacy@realvnc.com.
What is your right to object under data protection laws?
You have the right to object to us handling your personal information when:
We are handling your personal information based on our legitimate interests (as described in the “How do we use your data” section above). If you ask us to stop handling your personal information in this way, we will stop unless we can show you that we have compelling grounds as to why our use of your personal information should continue; or
For marketing purposes. If you ask us to stop handling your personal information on this basis, we will stop.
What are your other rights under data protection laws?
You have various rights under the data protection laws, which you can exercise by contacting us. The easiest way to do this is by email at privacy@realvnc.com.
Right of access
You are entitled to receive confirmation as to whether your personal information is being processed by us, as well as various other information relating to our use of your personal information.
You also have the right to access your personal information which we are handling.
Right to rectification
You have the right to require us to rectify any inaccurate personal information we hold about you. You also have the right to have incomplete personal information we hold about you completed, by providing a supplementary statement to us.
Right to restriction
You can restrict our processing of your personal information where:
You think we hold inaccurate personal information about you;
Our handling of your personal information breaks the law, but you do not want us to delete it;
We no longer need to process your personal information, but you want us to keep it for legal reasons; or
Where we are handling your personal information because we have a legitimate interest (as described in the “How do we use your data” section above, and are in the process of objecting to this use of your personal information.
Where you exercise your right to restrict us from using your personal information, we will then only process your personal information when you agree, except for storage purposes and to handle legal claims.
Right to data portability
You have the right to receive the personal information we hold about you in a structured, standard machine-readable format and to send this to another organisation controlling your personal information.
Right to erasure
You have the right to require us to erase your personal information which we are handling in the following circumstances:
Where we no longer need to use your personal information for the reasons we told you we collected it for;
Where we needed your consent to use your personal information and you have withdrawn your consent;
When you object to our use of your personal information and we have no compelling reason to carry on handling your personal information;
If our handling of your personal information has broken the law;
When we must erase your personal information to comply with a law we are subject to.
Right to complain
You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner's Office, the supervisory authority for data protection issues in England and Wales.
What about websites we link to?
Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks and affiliates.
Our site connects you to different websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites or use our services, please note that you have left our site and these websites have their own privacy policies.
We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies or websites. Please check their policies before you submit any personal information to these websites.
When will we change our privacy policy?
Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail or post.
Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.
How do you contact us with feedback?
Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcome and should be addressed to privacy@realvnc.com.
This privacy policy was last updated on 3 May 2019.
×
